Inventory of the Richard Hanser papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Richard Hanser papers
1937-1981
86011
Hoover Institution Archives
42 manuscript boxes (17.5 linear feet)
Television scripts, other writings, correspondence, notes, printed matter and other research materials relating to a wide variety of episodes in American and world history, including the 1923 putsch by Adolf Hitler, anti-Nazi resistance by students at the Universität München during World War II, and the role of humor in politics.
Hanser, Richard.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1986.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Richard Hanser (1909-1981) was an award-winning historical novelist and writer of television documentary series. A native of Buffalo, New York, Hanser was a descendant of three generations of clergymen. He prepared for the Protestant ministry at Concordia Lutheran Collegiate Institute in Bronxville, New York, before turning to journalism.
Hanser worked for The Buffalo Times, The Cleveland Press, and subsequently served as editor for Fawcett Publications. During the war, he served in the Office of War Information and created broadcasts for the office's psychological warfare department. Hanser joined the National Broadcasting Company (NBC) after World War II and co-wrote Victory at Sea, a naval history of the war, with television producer Henry Salomon.
The program, which was accompanied by the music of Richard Rodgers, won the George Foster Peabody Award and many other honors. Hanser also was the chief writer for NBC's Project XX series. His scripts included "Meet Mr. Lincoln," which won the Robert E. Sherwood Award; "Life in the Thirties"; "He is Risen"; and "Mark Twain's America," which won the Writers Guild of America Award.
Hanser's most noteworthy books include A Noble Treason: The Revolt of the Munich Students Against Hitler and Putsch: How Hitler Made Revolution.
Scope and Content of Collection
The Richard Hanser papers include biographical material, and research, production, and publicity material for the NBC television series Victory at Sea, Project XX, and Wisdom.
Documentation of the Project XX program is complete and includes scripts and drafts, correspondence, press releases, reviews, and other production information for 24 episodes. Victory at Sea is represented by narrations for all 26 episodes, a script for a motion picture version of the series (United Arts, 1954), and material pertaining to a book by Hanser and producer Henry J. Salomon, Jr. Also included are notes, scripts, and promotional material pertaining to five programs of the Wisdom series.
In addition to these major works, the collection contains a wide variety of notes from various research projects conducted by Hanser, ranging from Hitler and his colleagues to alcoholism in Russia during the 1970s. These research materials are comprised of Hanser's handwritten notes, newspaper clippings, photocopies, and other manuscripts.
Germany--History--Beer Hall Putsch, 1923.; Universität München.; Anti-Nazi movement.; National socialism.; World War, 1939-1945--Germany.; Hitler, Adolf, 1889-1945.; Political satire.
- J. C. historical clips, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 1: 1)
- Press quotes -- Jesus, 1973 September (Box-folder 1: 2)
- Jesus Christ Superstar, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 1: 3)
- Jesus transcripts (original), undated (Box-folder 1: 4)
- Jesus clippings, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 1: 5)
- Letters regarding publication of Jesus: What Manner of Man Is This?, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 1: 6)
- Manuscript: "The Glorious Hour of Lt. Monroe,", 1974 October 25 (Box-folder 1: 7)
- Simon and Schuster book catalogs/library catalogs, 1972 (Box-folder 1: 8)
- Mary R. O'Brien interview, 1976 January 3 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Hanser interview with Mary O'Brien regarding his recent book on James Monroe and his profession as a historical writer.
- Monroe comment, 1976 September (Box-folder 2: 2)
  Professional and press comments on Hanser's manuscript of his James Monroe book.
- Letters and royalty notes for the Monroe text, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 2: 3)
- J. Karl edits and comments on the Monroe manuscript, 1975 (Box-folder 2: 4)
- Submitted samples and comments from Jesus texts, 1971 (Box-folder 2: 5)
- S[imon] and S[chuster] correspondence on "Jesus" texts, 1972-1977 (Box-folder 2: 6)
- Hanser-selected Jesus quotes from the Bible, undated (Box-folder 2: 7)
- Miscellaneous Jesus notes and quotes, undated (Box-folder 2: 8)
- Miscellaneous letters on Jesus texts, 1981 (Box-folder 2: 9)
- Publicity from Jesus texts, 1972 (Box-folder 2: 10)
- Weedon copies from the Chicago Historical Society, 1973 (Box-folder 3: 1)
- Manuscripts by William S. Stryker in 1898, undated (Box-folder 3: 2)
  Writings on the Battles of Trenton and Princeton.
- Narratives, undated (Box-folder 3: 3-4)
- Biography notes, miscellaneous, undated (Box-folder 3: 5)
- Background on Washington's Crossing, undated (Box-folder 3: 6)
  Events leading up to Washington's crossing of the Hudson River.
- Promotion for Monroe biography, 1976 (Box-folder 3: 7)
- Book proposal: Lt. Monroe on the Delaware, 1972 September 19 (Box-folder 3: 8)
- Monroe -- personal biography, circa 1975 (Box-folder 3: 9-11)
  Research and letters regarding Hanser's writing of Monroe's biography.
- Research on Washington in New York, Long Island, and White Plains, undated (Box-folder 4: 1)
  Kip's Bay and Heathcote Hill, Fort Washington and Fort Lee, the Hickey Plot.
- Research on the Trenton Crossing, undated (Box-folder 4: 2)
  Includes more notes by Bancroft and Glover research.
- Williamsburg, William and Mary, J. Marshall, Virginia, 1954-1976 (Box-folder 4: 3)
- 3rd Virginia Regiment, 1973 October (Box-folder 4: 4)
- March North: Williamsburg to New York, undated (Box-folder 4: 5)
- Research on the Battle of Harlem Heights, undated (Box-folder 4: 6)
  Contains Weedon letters and Chilton letters.
- Treatment notes and queries, undated (Box-folder 4: 7)
- Monroe research correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 4: 8)
- New Jersey retreat research, undated (Box-folder 4: 9)
- Army: organization march/camp, undated (Box-folder 4: 10)
  U.S. Naval Institute proceedings pertaining to African Americans, militia, women, George Washington's trouble with deserters, food, drums, and sickness.
- Arms, rifles, muskets, and cannons research, undated (Box-folder 4: 11)
- Uniforms research, undated (Box-folder 4: 12)
- British Army research, undated (Box-folder 4: 13)
- Information on Hessians (miscellaneous), undated (Box-folder 4: 14)
- Victory at Sea, manuscript, 1958 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  Victory at Sea was originally a television miniseries (1952-1953), which Hanser collaborated on, that was about general warfare in World War II, particularly pertaining to the Navy. It also explored the industry in warfare. The manuscript is the book adaptation of the miniseries.
- "Midway,", 1952 April (Box-folder 5: 2)
  Manuscript of the "Midway" episode of the Victory at Sea television miniseries.
- "Mediterranean Mosaic,", 1952 August (Box-folder 5: 3)
  British forces head on to Gibraltar and Malta to hold off the Italian Navy and the German Luftwaffe from invading there. While the English do get constantly bombarded at the Malta Islands, they remain steadfastly determined to keep charging, especially after King George VI pays a visit.
- "Guadalcanal,", 1952 August (Box-folder 5: 4)
- "Rabaul,", 1952 July (Box-folder 5: 5)
  The title of this Victory at Sea episode refers to the circle of ships the militaries of the United States, Australia, and New Zealand manage to surround around the Japanese base of Rabaul in the Solomon Islands.
- "Anti-Submarine Warfare,", 1952 March (Box-folder 5: 6, Box-folder 5: 8)
- "Pearl Harbor,", 1952 March 24 (Box-folder 5: 7)
- Revised Jesus text, correspondence, and proof notes, 1972 April-May (Box-folder 5: 9)
- "Peleliu-Pelaw,", 1952 July 31 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  The United States prepares to attack the Japanese as they attempt to conquer Peleliu and Anguar near the Philippines.
- "Battle of Leyte,", undated (Box-folder 6: 2)
- "Return of the Allies: Philippines,", 1952 November (Box-folder 6: 3)
- "Submarines,", 1953 January (Box-folder 6: 4)
  In this episode of Victory at Sea the U.S. submarines contributed to the sinking of thousands of Japanese battleships.
- "The Fate of Europe,", 1953 February (Box-folder 6: 5)
- "Suribachi -- Iwo Jima,", 1953 March (Box-folder 6: 6)
- "The Road to Mandalay," China, Burma, and India, 1952 January (Box-folder 6: 7)
  This episode details Japan's invasion of China in 1936 and the subsequent conquest of Burma after Pearl Harbor.
- "Suicide for Glory" -- Okinawa, 1953 March (Box-folder 6: 8)
- "Design for Peace,", 1953 February (Box-folder 6: 9)
- Victory at Sea, book text II, 1958 June 17 (Box-folder 6: 10)
- "The American Experience,", 1972 September 22 (Box-folder 7: 1)
- "Mare Nostrum,", 1952 July (Box-folder 7: 2)
- "Sea and Sand," North Africa, 1952 October (Box-folder 7: 3)
  In this episode, the U.S. Army goes forward to defeat German General Rommel's military men in North Africa while the Allies also overtake many of the Mediterranean supply bases.
- "Beneath the Southern Cross," South Atlantic, 1952 July (Box-folder 7: 4)
  This episode portrays the battle of the South Atlantic between the British ship Devonshire and the German ship Atlantis.
- "The Magnetic North," Murmansk -- Alaska, 1952 January (Box-folder 7: 5)
  This episode of Victory at Sea explores the battles between the Americans and the Germans over the Arctic Circle concerning the Nazi-occupied Norwegians. After the Germans' defeat, the Japanese take their turn, resulting in another long, drawn out battle.
- "The Conquest of Micronesia,", 1952 September (Box-folder 7: 6)
- "New Guinea,", 1952 September (Box-folder 7: 7)
- "Roman Renaissance,", 1952 December (Box-folder 7: 8)
- "D-Day," Normandy, 1952 May (Box-folder 7: 9)
- "Killers and the Killed," anti-submarine warfare, 1952 October (Box-folder 7: 10)
  Although Germany's surface fleet is no longer a factor beyond D-Day, its submarine packs continue to wreak havoc upon the Allied convoys that are vital to the survival of troops fighting in France. The Allies develop new ways to counter and destroy the U-Boat threat so that the Atlantic Ocean can continue to serve as the pipeline to victory in Europe.
- "The Turkey Shoot,", 1952 November (Box-folder 7: 11)
- Hitler early history, undated (Box-folder 8: 1)
- Hitler miscellaneous topics, undated (Box-folder 8: 2)
- Hitler's views on Germany, commanders, pre-WWII, undated (Box-folder 8: 3)
- Hitler personality, undated (Box-folder 8: 4)
  Various notes on Hitler's habits, viewpoints, and personal details.
- Hitler WWI miscellaneous, undated (Box-folder 9: 1)
  Hitler's acquaintances, ideologies, and other projects after World War I.
- Pre-WWI miscellaneous, undated (Box-folder 9: 2)
  Materials regarding Lenin in Munich, Munich Revolution, FEME, and political murders.
- Post-WWI miscellaneous, undated (Box-folder 9: 3)
  Materials regarding intellectuals, Versailles Treaty, Anti-Weimar campaign.
- Nazi-Germany miscellaneous, undated (Box-folder 9: 4)
  Storm Troopers' evolutions: uniform, flag, and salutes.
- Munich miscellaneous, 1920-1922 (Box-folder 9: 5)
- Hitler inner personality, undated (Box-folder 10: 1)
  Details on Hitler and religion, humor, his inner circle.
- Munich miscellaneous, 1920-1922 (Box-folder 10: 2)
- Hitler miscellaneous, post-WWI, 1923-1924 (Box-folder 10: 3)
  Documents regarding trial, prison, and putsch attempt.
- World War I details, undated (Box-folder 10: 4)
  The Kaiser, the collapse and end of World War I.
- Hitler personality, undated (Box-folder 10: 5)
- Hitler associations post-WWI and WWII, undated (Box-folder 11: 1-2)
- Motion picture manuscripts, 1954-1960 (Box-folder 12: 1-3)
- "Life in the Thirties," broadcast manuscript, 1959 (Box-folder 13: 1)
  A documentary film portraying life in America during the 1930s.
- "Mark Twain's America," broadcast manuscript, 1960 April (Box-folder 13: 2)
- Victory at Sea, 90-minute special version, 1960 November (Box-folder 13: 3)
  Shortened version of the popular television series portraying combat (mostly naval) during World War II.
- "The Coming of Christ," broadcast manuscript, 1960 December (Box-folder 13: 4)
- "Laughter USA," broadcast manuscript, 1961 (Box-folder 13: 5)
- "The Story of Will Rogers," broadcast manuscript, 1961 (Box-folder 13: 6)
- Truman Smith report, 1963 July 1 (Box-folder 13: 7)
- "That War in Korea," broadcast manuscript, 1963 September (Box-folder 13: 8)
  Pertaining to the events of the Korean War.
- Miscellaneous book outlines, 1969 September 9 (Box-folder 13: 9)
- The New York Times, book review, 1971 January 17 (Box-folder 13: 10)
- Project XX broadcasts, 1962-1969 (Box-folder 13: 11-13)
- "Putsch!" (yellow copy), 1968 February (Box-folder 14: 1-5)
  Story on the origins of Hitler's coming to power through the onset of Revolution.
- Letters and commentary on "Putsch" text, undated (Box-folder 14: 6)
- Steno notebooks, undated (Box-folder 14: 7)
- Scheider Bericht reports, undated (Box-folder 14: 8-10)
- Führer persönlich, 1943-1960 (Box-folder 15: 1)
- Hitler: personal details, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 15: 2)
- Hitler background quotes, 1956 (Box-folder 15: 3)
- Haarmann, Denke, Kuertin, etc., 1962 (Box-folder 15: 4)
  Cannibalism in Germany photostats from Colin Wilson's Encyclopedia of Murder.
- Future books; references; nationlist-socialist Germany, 1964 (Box-folder 15: 5)
  Notes from Professor Hunt at Harvard.
- Hitler olio, 1966 (Box-folder 15: 6)
- "Putsch!" (yellow copy), 1968 February (Box-folder 15: 7)
- Tucholsky -- Prediction of 3rd Reich Revival notes, 1969 (Box-folder 15: 8)
- Expressionism and Dadaism, 1966-1970 (Box-folder 15: 9)
  Blain Reiter clipping.
- "Putsch!,", 1970 (Box-folder 15: 10)
- Hemingway, undated (Box-folder 15: 11)
  Regardging inflation and Ruhr.
- Hitler's 2nd Book/Will, undated (Box-folder 15: 12)
  Hitler's analysis on why he lost the war ( Spiegel).
- Psychologist quotes on Adolf Hitler, undated (Box-folder 15: 13)
- "The Twisted Cross," original script, 1956 March (Box-folder 16: 1)
  Broadcast concerning the origins of the 3rd Reich and the Nazi socialist movement.
- Munich notes, 1965-1980 (Box-folder 16: 2-4)
  Notes on Hitler, addresses in Munich, mixed newspaper clippings.
- Bavaria, 1964-1966 (Box-folder 16: 5)
- Wederkind clips, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 16: 6)
- Beer (and Munich), 1968-1969 (Box-folder 16: 7)
- Chronology: From Death of Queen Victoria in 1901 to 1930, undated (Box-folder 16: 8)
- Postwar Germany -- SA, undated (Box-folder 16: 9)
- Putsch, prison, and agitation, undated (Box-folder 16: 10)
- Hitler -- elections and power, undated (Box-folder 16: 11)
- Notes on Goering, Hess, and Goebbels, undated (Box-folder 16: 12)
- Terror, SS, and KZ, undated (Box-folder 16: 13)
- Masses and marching, undated (Box-folder 16: 14)
- Berchtes Gaden-War (Munich), undated (Box-folder 16: 15)
- Nemesis -- End of the war, undated (Box-folder 16: 16)
- Rathenan series ("Wset am Sonntag"), undated (Box-folder 16: 17)
- "World in Trance,", undated (Box-folder 16: 18)
- Liebknecht-Luxemburg murders, 1919 January 15 (Box-folder 17: 1)
  Composed of Spiegel and Major Pabst interviews, as well as a Monat article.
- "Adolf Hitler im Felde,", undated (Box-folder 17: 2)
- Notes of Karl May, undated (Box-folder 17: 3)
- Hitler trial -- prison, 1962 (Box-folder 17: 4)
- "History of Civilization,", 1967 February (Box-folder 17: 5)
- New York Post "Putsch!" publicity, 1971 (Box-folder 17: 6)
- "Putsch!" promotion comments, undated (Box-folder 17: 7)
- "Putsch!" in Britain, undated (Box-folder 17: 8)
- "Putsch!" letters, 1970-1976 (Box-folder 17: 9)
- Newspaper clippings and ads, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 17: 10)
- Rundschau -- An American-German review, 1971 May (Box-folder 17: 11)
- "Pyramid," paperback, 1979 (Box-folder 17: 12)
- Rodell (Fawcett) and Hitler, 1961-1975 (Box-folder 18: 1)
  Correspondence and notes between Hanser and Marie Rodell, a literary agent and author.
- "Putsch!," notes and clippings, 1961-1966 (Box-folder 18: 2)
- Library of Congress: Government Archives, 1962 (Box-folder 18: 3)
- "Putsch!" correspondence -- answered and source addresses, 1962-1971 (Box-folder 18: 4)
- "Putsch!" correspondence -- Prentice Hall, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 18: 5)
- The Arts: Saturday Review, 1972 March 25 (Box-folder 18: 6)
  The Summer Olympics -- Munich and the German World.
- Schwabing, Munich, 1966 April (Box-folder 18: 7)
- "Putsch!" Notes #2, 1967-1972 (Box-folder 18: 8)
- Bergman "Putsch!" film, 1976 (Box-folder 18: 9)
- "Whisper-Jokes," proposal and correspondence, 1976 Fall (Box-folder 18: 10)
- Fall Kahr - Beer hall details and Putsch, 1980 (Box-folder 18: 11)
- Book burning notes, 1968-1979 (Box-folder 18: 12)
- "Putsch!" march, 1951-1968 (Box-folder 18: 13)
  Ludendorff - "Wir Marschieren."
- "Putsch!" art, undated (Box-folder 18: 14)
- "Putsch!" correspondence -- active, 1961-1970 (Box-folder 18: 15)
  Hoover Institute - Prof. Abel and Prof. Gordon.
- "Gallows Humor,", 1947, 1951 (Box-folder 19: 1)
  Includes clippings Hanser collected on the subject.
- Kohout, 1953, 1954 (Box-folder 19: 2)
  Materials include Hanser's notes regarding him and his works.
- "Graffiti,", 1966-1976 (Box-folder 19: 3)
- Rodell (non-Wyden), 1970-1973 (Box-folder 19: 4)
- Soviet drinking, circa 1970 (Box-folder 19: 5)
  Notes on Soviet alcoholism and other drinking problems relating to the economy, the workforce, and society.
- Book proposals, 1976, 1979, 1980 (Box-folder 19: 6)
- Richard Hanser biographies, 1980 (Box-folder 19: 7)
- "Wit as a Weapon,", undated (Box-folder 19: 8)
- "Comedian on the Firing Line,", undated (Box-folder 19: 9)
- Research materials, notes, clippings
  - Psychosis, 1970s (Box-folder 20: 1)
  - Wartime spies, 1960s (Box-folder 20: 2)
  - Cricket in Britain, 1960s (Box-folder 20: 3)
  - Rote Kappele and Lucy spy ring, 1960s (Box-folder 20: 4)
  - German youth movements, 1970s (Box-folder 20: 5)
  - Russian sex-spies, 1970s (Box-folder 20: 6)
  - Female Russian spies, 1970s (Box-folder 20: 7)
  - Communist youth parties, 1970s (Box-folder 20: 8)
  - U.S. pop music, 1970s (Box-folder 21: 1)
  - Nazis and jazz, 1970 (Box-folder 21: 2)
  - Psychoanalysis, 1960s (Box-folder 21: 3)
  - Assorted research topics, 1970s (Box-folder 21: 4)
  - Neo-Nazism, 1970s (Box-folder 22: 1)
  - Das Parlament, newspaper, 1952 (Box-folder 22: 2)
  - Sex scandals in Nazi high command, 1970s (Box-folder 22: 3)
  - Vienna, 1970 (Box-folder 22: 4)
  - German duelling, 1970s (Box-folder 22: 5)
  - German jazz music, undated (Box-folder 22: 6)
  - Jazz music in Russia, 1970s (Box-folder 22: 7)
- "Town Hall Tonight," script, undated (Box-folder 23: 1)
- "Hitler Takes a Ribbing from the Germans,", 1947 (Box-folder 23: 2)
- Comical Communists, 1950-1975 (Box-folder 23: 3)
- "Count Bobby," printed materials, 1970 (Box-folder 23: 4)
- Clips on German humor, 1960 (Box-folder 23: 5)
- Writings on German humor, 1960s (Box-folder 23: 6)
- Notes, correspondence, writings on German resistance, 1960 (Box-folder 23: 7)
- East Germany, 1970 (Box-folder 23: 8)
- German war criminals (Spandau), 1960s (Box-folder 23: 9)
- Political humor clippings
  - Reagan humor clippings, 1970-1980s (Box-folder 24: 1)
  - Gerald Ford humor, 1980s (Box-folder 24: 2)
  - Jimmy Carter humor, 1970s (Box-folder 24: 3)
  - General presidential humor, 1970s (Box-folder 24: 4)
  - Adlai Stevenson humor, 1970s (Box-folder 24: 5)
  - Republican humor, 1980s (Box-folder 24: 6)
  - Historical and contemporary political humor, 1960s (Box-folder 24: 7)
  - General political humor, 1960-1979 (Box-folder 24: 8)
  - International political humor, 1970s (Box-folder 24: 9)
  - "Laughter USA," clippings, 1970s (Box-folder 24: 10)
- Collected material, 1960s-1970s (Box-folder 25: 1-2)
- Published articles, 1950s (Box-folder 25: 3)
- "Iron Curtain Humor,", 1954 (Box-folder 25: 4)
- "Weekend," anti-Soviet jokes, 1960s (Box-folder 25: 5)
- Article ideas, 1950s-1960s (Box-folder 25: 6)
- Joke books, 1970s (Box-folder 25: 7)
- News clippings regarding Italy, 1970s (Box-folder 25: 8)
- General American humor, 1970s (Box-folder 25: 9)
- Russia jokes, 1970s (Box-folder 26: 1)
- Czech humor, 1960s-1970s (Box-folder 26: 2)
- Iron Curtain jokes, 1970s (Box-folder 26: 3-4)
- "Official Humor," magazines, 1970s (Box-folder 27: 1)
- "Heritage," American sayings, 1970s (Box-folder 27: 2)
- England, post-war Germany, 1970s (Box-folder 27: 3)
- "Joke's on Us,", 1970s (Box-folder 27: 4)
- Hans Schmidt humor, 1970s (Box-folder 27: 5)
- Nazi era humor, 1970s (Box-folder 27: 6)
- American humor, 1970s (Box-folder 27: 7)
- Articles on political humor, 1970s (Box-folder 27: 8)
- "Mirror of America," research materials and notes, 1970s (Box-folder 28: 1)
- "Mirror of America," research, outlines, and notes, 1970s (Box-folder 28: 2)
- "Mirror of America," shot list, 1970s (Box-folder 28: 3)
- Project XX, information, 1970s (Box-folder 28: 4-5)
- Lincoln outlines, 1970 (Box-folder 29: 1)
- George Washington research, 1970s (Box-folder 29: 2)
- George Marshall research, scripts, and documents, 1960s (Box-folder 29: 3)
- Misquotes, 1960s-1970s (Box-folder 29: 4)
- Humor, quotes, and satire clippings, 1960s (Box-folder 29: 5)
- France and other countries, 1960s (Box-folder 29: 6)
- "Hazards of Humor,", 1960s (Box-folder 29: 7)
- WWI research, 1960s (Box-folder 30: 1)
- Continuity outlines on George Washington, 1960s (Box-folder 30: 2)
- George Washington program notes, scripts, awards info, and outlines, 1960s (Box-folder 30: 3)
- Lincoln program script, shot list, and publicity, 1960s (Box-folder 30: 4)
- Mark Twain research, 1960s (Box-folder 31: 1)
- "The Coming," shot list, 1960 (Box-folder 31: 2)
- "Risen," scripts and shot list, 1960s (Box-folder 31: 3)
- Jazz research, 1960s (Box-folder 31: 4)
- Stock market research, 1960s (Box-folder 31: 5)
- WWI research, 1960s (Box-folder 31: 6)
- Published works, 1960s-1970s (Box-folder 31: 7)
- Assorted publications, 1960s (Box-folder 32: 1)
- USS Edsall TV story, 1960s (Box-folder 32: 2)
- Twain research, 1960s (Box-folder 32: 3)
- Publications, 1959-1969 (Box-folder 33: 1-4)
- Goering review, 1974 (Box-folder 34: 1)
- Publications, 1947-1979 (Box-folder 34: 2-5)
- Correspondence and newspaper, 1970s (Box-folder 35: 1)
- Newspapers, 1970 (Box-folder 35: 2-3)
- The New Leader, magazine, 1952-1969 (Box-folder 35: 4-5)
- Newspapers, 1951-1971 (Box-folder 36: 1-2)
- Correspondence, 1970s (Box-folder 36: 3)
- Book reviews, 1970s (Box-folder 36: 4)
- Quotes, 1970s (Box-folder 36: 5)
- Spiral notebooks, 1970s (Box-folder 37: 1)
- Research and correspondence, 1970s (Box-folder 37: 2)
- "A Noble Treason," script, 1980 (Box-folder 37: 3-4)
- Newspapers, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 37: 5)
- "White Rose," discards and re-dos, 1979 (Box-folder 38: 1)
- "A Noble Treason," script, 1980 (Box-folder 38: 2)
- Magazines, 1949-1957 (Box-folder 38: 3)
- News clippings, 1981 (Box-folder 38: 4)
- "The White Rose and the Swastika," script, 1980 (Box-folder 38: 5-6)